The first casualty of war is innocence.
Platoon is a drama, war, action film directed by Oliver Stone.
As a young and naive recruit in Vietnam, Chris Taylor faces a moral crisis
when confronted with the horrors of war and the duality of man.
Chris Taylor, played by Charlie Sheen.
Sergeant Elias Grodin, played by Willem Dafoe.
Sergeant Robert "Bob" Barnes, played by Tom Berenger.
Bunny, played by Kevin Dillon.
Big Harold, played by Forest Whitaker.
Lieutenant Wolfe, played by Mark Moses.
Platoon is a 1986 American anti-war film written and directed by Oliver Stone, starring Tom
Berenger, Willem Dafoe, Charlie Sheen, Keith David, Kevin Dillon, John C.
McGinley, Forest Whitaker, and Johnny Depp.
It is the first film of a trilogy of Vietnam War films directed by Stone, followed
by Born on the Fourth of July (1989) and Heaven & Earth (1993).
The film, based on Stone's experience from the war, follows a new U.S.
Army volunteer (Sheen) serving in Vietnam while his Platoon Sergeant and his Squad Leader
(Berenger and Dafoe) argue over the morality in the platoon and of the war itself.
Stone wrote the screenplay based upon his experiences as a U.S.
infantryman in Vietnam, to counter the vision of the war
portrayed in John Wayne's The Green Berets.
Although he wrote scripts for films such as Midnight Express and Scarface, Stone struggled to get the
film developed until Hemdale Film Corporation acquired the project along with Salvador.
Filming took place in the Philippines in February 1986 and lasted 54 days.
Platoon was the first Hollywood film to be written and
directed by a veteran of the Vietnam War.
Platoon was released by Orion Pictures on December 19, 1986.
Upon its release, Platoon received critical acclaim for Stone's directing and screenplay,
cinematography, the battle sequences' realism, and the performances of Sheen, Dafoe, and Berenger.
The film was a box office success upon its release, grossing $137.9 million domestically against
its $6 million budget, becoming the third highest-grossing domestic film of 1986.
The film was nominated for eight Academy Awards at the 59th Academy Awards, and won four:
Best Picture, Best Director for Stone, Best Sound, and Best Film Editing.
In 1998, the American Film Institute placed Platoon
at #83 in their "AFI's 100 Years ...
100 Movies" poll.
In 2019, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of dying and death, vietnam
war, helicopter, ambush, war crimes.
The tone is emotional and dark and thought_provoking.